hi in this video we learn how to trace the recursive function and how to write
a recurrence relation and how to solve a recurrence relation so I am taking
one of the example then in the other videos you can find following examples
more examples will come in other videos let us start already I have an
algorithm or function here a C language function I have written you
call it as algorithm also test is a function which is taking n as input and
if n is greater than 0 it is printing the value and then it is calling itself
for n minus 1 so I will take some sample value and test it suppose I am
calling this function by passing 3 let us see what happens if I pass 3 test
3 3 is greater than 0 yes 3 is greater than 0 print 3 so it will print 3 then
call itself for 3 minus 1 that is 2 so call test 2 then for 2 again it's a
1 is greater than 0 so it's a recursive call again for this one as it
is greater than 0 it will print 1 and call itself for test 0 now when it is
0 0 is not greater than 0 so it will not call itself and it will stop
doesn't go further so this is a tracing tree for this particular function or
recursive function I have passed 3 so what is the time taken by this one so
let us see what it is doing and this call it is printing a value then
calling again printing a value and calling again printing a value and
calling again so the amount of work done is just printing value how many